Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Li Jen-yao.
لي جين ياو.
Don't worry. We're here to help you.
لا تقلق. نحن هنا لمساعدتك.
Tell us how you got these injuries.
أخبرنا كيف أصبت بهذه الإصابات.
How dare you do it.
كيف تجرؤ على فعل ذلك؟
Fuck!
اللعنة!
Jen-yao! Listen to me!
جين ياو! استمع إلي!
No!
لا!
Go inside!
ادخل إلى الداخل!
Li Jen-yao, stop wasting time.
لي جين ياو، توقف عن إضاعة الوقت.
Just tell the school counselor.
أخبر المرشد الطلابي بالمدرسة.
Did the injuries on your face come from classmates,
هل الإصابات التي ظهرت على وجهك كانت بسبب زملائك في الدراسة؟
or did you get into trouble outside of school?
أم أنك تورطت في مشاكل خارج المدرسة؟
If your dad doesn't show up again next week,
إذا لم يظهر والدك مرة أخرى الأسبوع المقبل،
we'll come back.
سنعود.
When that happens,
عندما يحدث ذلك،
we won't be so courteous.
لن نكون بهذه اللطافة.
Got it?
فهمتها؟
You're back.
لقد عدت.
What are you looking at? Huh?
ماذا تنظر إليه؟ هاه؟
What are you looking at?
ما الذي تنظر إليه؟
He did nothing. Don't throw drunken tantrums.
لم يفعل شيئاً. لا تتصرف بغضب وأنت ثمل.
Jen-yao, go study--
جين ياو، اذهب للدراسة --
Get lost! What the hell are you looking at?
انصرف! ما الذي تنظر إليه بحق الجحيم؟
No!
لا!
-What are you looking at? -Don't do this!
- ما الذي تنظر إليه؟ - لا تفعل هذا!
No! Don't do this!
لا! لا تفعل هذا!
Fuck you! Fuck!
تباً لك! تباً!
Fuck!
اللعنة!
I fell off a motorbike and got hurt.
سقطت من دراجة نارية وأصبت.
What? You fell off a motorbike?
ماذا؟ سقطت من دراجة نارية؟
Yes.
نعم.
I didn't tell you earlier because I don't have a driver's license,
لم أخبرك بذلك سابقاً لأنني لا أملك رخصة قيادة.
so I was afraid I'd get a demerit or be punished.
لذلك كنت أخشى أن أحصل على خصم من نقاطي أو أن أتعرض للعقاب.
Is that good enough?
هل هذا جيد بما فيه الكفاية؟
Can I go back to class now?
هل يمكنني العودة إلى الفصل الآن؟
Li Jen-yao,
لي جين ياو,
please trust that we'll always stand by our students.
يرجى الثقة بأننا سنقف دائماً إلى جانب طلابنا.
So whatever happens in the future,
لذا مهما حدث في المستقبل،
you can come to me if you need help.
يمكنك اللجوء إليّ إذا كنت بحاجة إلى مساعدة.
I want to get spicy hot pot.
أريد أن أحصل على طبق هوت بوت حار.
How is that sweet?
ما أجمل ذلك؟
Let's get cake.
هيا بنا نحضر الكعكة.
Hot pot causes acne.
يُسبب طبق الحساء الساخن ظهور حب الشباب.
-Let's get spicy hot pot. -Yeah.
- لنحضر طبق هوت بوت حار. - أجل.
I want to get youtiao too.
أريد الحصول على يوتياو أيضاً.
-I'm going upstairs. Bye! -Bye!
- سأصعد إلى الطابق العلوي. مع السلامة! - مع السلامة!
HAD I NOT SEEN THE SUN
لو لم أرَ الشمس
This is for you.
هذا لك.
Take it.
خذها.
Your stomach growled from hunger.
قرقرت معدتك من الجوع.
Just eat it.
كلّه فحسب.
Why don't you eat?
لماذا لا تأكل؟
I'm in the dance class.
أنا في فصل الرقص.
All of us have to watch our weight so that we're ready for the performance.
علينا جميعاً أن نراقب وزننا حتى نكون مستعدين للأداء.
But I think I'm getting too heavy.
لكنني أعتقد أنني أصبحتُ أثقل من اللازم.
Yet my mom still prepares big lunches for me.
ومع ذلك، لا تزال أمي تعد لي وجبات غداء كبيرة.
But you don't look very heavy.
لكنك لا تبدو سميناً جداً.
Of course I don't.
بالطبع لا أفعل.
I didn't say I'm too heavy, just that I'm getting there.
لم أقل إنني أعاني من زيادة الوزن، بل قلت فقط إنني في طريقي إلى ذلك.
Hey.
يا.
Just take it as me wanting to lose weight, but not waste food.
اعتبروا الأمر مجرد رغبة مني في إنقاص الوزن، ولكن دون إهدار الطعام.
Finish my lunch for me.
أنهِ غدائي نيابةً عني.
Damn it. It's a chicken drumstick.
اللعنة! إنها قطعة من فخذ الدجاج.
What? Hurry up and eat.
ماذا؟ أسرع وتناول الطعام.
You look even hungrier than me. Why did you give me your lunch?
تبدو أكثر جوعاً مني. لماذا أعطيتني غداءك؟
I can't eat more.
لا أستطيع أن آكل أكثر.
Also, sneaking off to buy lunch like this is against school rules.
كما أن التسلل لشراء الغداء بهذه الطريقة مخالف لقواعد المدرسة.
Not if I don't get caught.
ليس إن لم يتم القبض عليّ.
-Sir. -Yes?
-سيدي. -نعم؟
-One pork ribs bento. -One pork ribs bento, okay.
- علبة بينتو واحدة من أضلاع لحم الخنزير. - علبة بينتو واحدة من أضلاع لحم الخنزير، حسناً.
Hey, I don't want pork ribs.
مهلاً، لا أريد أضلاع لحم الخنزير.
I want a drumstick.
أريد قطعة دجاج.
-Sir. -Yes?
-سيدي. -نعم؟
-A drumstick instead. -No problem.
- بدلاً من ذلك، قطعة من فخذ الدجاج. - لا مشكلة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
It's the military instructor. Let's go.
إنه المدرب العسكري. هيا بنا.
Why haven't you finished your lunch? You're a slow eater.
لماذا لم تنهِ غداءك؟ أنت تأكل ببطء.
That's because you ate fast.
ذلك لأنك أكلت بسرعة.
You said you wanted to lose weight,
قلت إنك تريد إنقاص وزنك،
but you finished a drumstick bento in minutes.
لكنك أنهيت وجبة بينتو من أفخاذ الدجاج في دقائق.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
Only three days after going on a diet
بعد ثلاثة أيام فقط من اتباع نظام غذائي
and I ate a whole bento.
وأكلت علبة بينتو كاملة.
Oh no!
يا إلهي!
I'm going to fail tomorrow's weight check.
سأفشل في اختبار الوزن غداً.
You can't say a word about what happened just now.
لا يمكنك أن تنطق بكلمة واحدة عما حدث للتو.
Do you mean failing to lose weight
هل تقصد عدم القدرة على إنقاص الوزن؟
or scarfing down a drumstick bento in three minutes?
أم التهام وجبة بينتو من أفخاذ الدجاج في ثلاث دقائق؟
Both! Say a word and you're dead.
كلاهما! قل كلمة واحدة وستكون ميتاً.
I have dance practice this afternoon. Gotta head back to class.
لديّ حصة رقص بعد الظهر. يجب أن أعود إلى الصف.
Bye-bye.
وداعا وداعا.
Li Jen-yao.
لي جين ياو.
Okay, I got it.
حسناً، فهمت.
My name is Chiang Hsiao-tung. You'll be here at noon tomorrow, right?
اسمي تشيانغ شياو تونغ. ستكون هنا ظهر غد، أليس كذلك؟
Then I'll give you my lunch tomorrow too.
سأعطيك غدائي غداً أيضاً.
Bye-bye.
وداعا وداعا.
OCEAN DRAGON SEAFOOD
مأكولات بحرية أوشن دراغون
Only three days after going on a diet
بعد ثلاثة أيام فقط من اتباع نظام غذائي
and I ate a whole bento.
وأكلت علبة بينتو كاملة.
Oh no!
يا إلهي!
Jen-yao.
جين ياو.
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Why the smile?
لماذا هذه الابتسامة؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Are the customers done? I'll clean up.
هل انتهى الزبائن؟ سأقوم بالتنظيف.
Hey, here.
مرحباً، تفضل.
Here. Your salary for the month.
هذا راتبك لهذا الشهر.
You've worked quite hard this month.
لقد بذلت جهداً كبيراً هذا الشهر.
Here's 2,000 dollars extra.
إليك ألفي دولار إضافية.
Take it.
خذها.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
YI-NO HIGH SCHOOL
مدرسة يي نو الثانوية
I waited ages for you. Let's go.
انتظرتك طويلاً. هيا بنا.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Get in.
أدخل.
Kiddo.
يا صغيري.
Off work, huh?
إجازة من العمل، أليس كذلك؟
Are you going home?
هل ستعود إلى المنزل؟
We'll give you a ride
سنوصلك
so we can say hi to your dad.
حتى نتمكن من إلقاء التحية على والدك.
He hasn't been home for ages.
لم يعد إلى المنزل منذ زمن طويل.
I don't know where he is. I don't want to know.
لا أعرف أين هو. ولا أريد أن أعرف.
Don't come to me again.
لا تعد إليّ مرة أخرى.
If your dad hasn't been home,
إذا لم يكن والدك في المنزل،
how did you get this wound on your face?
كيف أصبت بهذه الجرحة في وجهك؟
You're really unlucky to have such a savage father.
أنت حقاً سيء الحظ لأن لديك أباً بهذه القسوة.
What?
ماذا؟
Hurts too much to breathe?
هل يؤلمك التنفس بشدة؟
My boss used to hit me like that when I didn't collect all the debts.
كان مديري يضربني هكذا عندما لا أجمع كل الديون.
Don't be scared. You'll be fine in a few minutes.
لا تخف. ستكون بخير في غضون دقائق قليلة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'll be straight with you.
سأكون صريحاً معك.
Man, I've been collecting debts for over a decade.
يا رجل، لقد كنت أجمع الديون لأكثر من عقد من الزمان.
I've seen a lot of savages like your dad.
لقد رأيت الكثير من المتوحشين مثل والدك.
With a dad like that,
مع أب كهذا،
it doesn't matter how hard you work.
لا يهم مدى الجهد الذي تبذله في العمل.
You'll never amount to anything.
لن تصبح شيئاً يُذكر.
The money from today
الأموال من اليوم
will cover your dad's interest for the week.
سيغطي ذلك فوائد والدك لهذا الأسبوع.
If your dad doesn't show up next week,
إذا لم يحضر والدك الأسبوع المقبل،
I guess we won't bother.
أظن أننا لن نكلف أنفسنا عناء ذلك.
I'll just come to you from then on.
سأعود إليك من الآن فصاعدًا.
Kiddo!
يا صغيري!
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Mom, don't say anything. Come with me.
أمي، لا تقولي شيئاً. تعالي معي.
Jen-yao.
جين ياو.
Jen-yao, what's wrong? What's…
جين ياو، ما الخطب؟ ما...
-Hey, you guys-- -Mom, calm down.
-يا جماعة-- -أمي، اهدئي.
What the hell? Fuck you!
ما هذا بحق الجحيم؟ تباً لك!
Are you gonna pay up?
هل ستدفع؟
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
No, don't do this.
لا، لا تفعل هذا.
Mom!
أم!
Forget him already.
انساه الآن.
What do you mean, "forget him"? He's your dad!
ماذا تقصد بـ "انساه"؟ إنه والدك!
Mom.
أم.
Let go of me, Li Jen-yao!
اتركني يا لي جين ياو!
Wake up!
استيقظ!
Do you know how he treats us?
هل تعلم كيف يعاملنا؟
He doesn't deserve to be my dad.
هو لا يستحق أن يكون والدي.
He's the one who's deep in debt.
هو الشخص المثقل بالديون.
Why should we suffer? Have you thought about that?
لماذا يجب أن نعاني؟ هل فكرت في ذلك؟
Go ahead, keep hiding.
استمر في الاختباء.
Hand over the money.
سلم المال.
Don't worry, okay?
لا تقلق، حسناً؟
I've talked to them.
لقد تحدثت معهم.
They'll go to him for money from now on and leave us alone.
سيذهبون إليه من الآن فصاعداً ليطلبوا المال، وسيتركوننا وشأننا.
Mom,
أم،
we're finally rid of him.
لقد تخلصنا منه أخيراً.
So
لذا
you're the one who handed him over?
أنت من سلمته؟
He asked for it.
لقد طلب ذلك.
He is your dad!
إنه والدك!
He's your dad, no matter what!
هو والدك، مهما حدث!
Chicken heart, got it.
قلب دجاجة، فهمت.
-And two corn on the cobs, okay. -Zucchinis are good.
- وحبتان من الذرة المشوية، حسناً. - الكوسا لذيذة.
-Try them. They're good. -That's right.
- جربها. إنها جيدة. - هذا صحيح.
Then some zucchinis, please.
ثم بعض الكوسا، من فضلك.
Sure. Zucchinis are healthy.
بالتأكيد. الكوسا مفيدة للصحة.
-And some green bell peppers. -Good order. Green bell peppers are great.
- وبعض الفلفل الأخضر. - طلب جيد. الفلفل الأخضر رائع.
Stop fooling around. Give it to me.
كفى عبثاً. أعطني إياه.
-Customers are waiting. -Fine.
- الزبائن ينتظرون. - حسناً.
My bad.
خطأي.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Our roasted chicken hearts are good.
قلوب الدجاج المشوية لدينا لذيذة.
-Want some? -Sure.
- هل تريد بعضاً؟ - بالتأكيد.
Sorry for the wait. That'll be 100 dollars.
أعتذر عن التأخير. سيكون المبلغ 100 دولار.
-Thank you.
شكراً لك.
Come again. Bye.
تفضل بزيارتنا مرة أخرى. مع السلامة.
You ordered non-spicy, right?
لقد طلبت طعامًا غير حار، أليس كذلك؟
-Yes, non-spicy. -Okay, non-spicy.
- نعم، غير حار. - حسناً، غير حار.
Looks like I can consider you for the solo at the end-of-semester show.
يبدو أنني أستطيع أن أضعك في الاعتبار للعزف المنفرد في عرض نهاية الفصل الدراسي.
But you must continue maintaining this state.
لكن يجب عليك الاستمرار في الحفاظ على هذه الحالة.
Let's take ten.
لنأخذ عشرة.
Hsiao-tung, I told you. You can do it.
شياو تونغ، لقد أخبرتك. يمكنك فعلها.
Yeah, I was so happy for you just now.
نعم، كنت سعيداً جداً من أجلك الآن.
You're reading too much into it.
أنت تبالغ في تفسير الأمر.
It's too soon to celebrate.
من السابق لأوانه الاحتفال.
The teacher said she'd consider it. Nothing's decided yet.
قالت المعلمة إنها ستفكر في الأمر. لم يُحسم شيء بعد.
Who else could it be but you?
من غيرك يمكن أن يكون؟
That's right. If it's being considered, it's as good as certain.
هذا صحيح. إذا كان الأمر قيد الدراسة، فهو أمر شبه مؤكد.
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
Give me a second.
انتظرني لحظة.
Li Jen-yao.
لي جين ياو.
Go away!
يبتعد!
Fuck! Are you nuts?
تباً! هل أنت مجنون؟
What did I do? Why are you doing this to me?
ماذا فعلت؟ لماذا تفعلون بي هذا؟
You forgot already?
هل نسيت بالفعل؟
What are you talking about?
عن ماذا تتحدث؟
Please let me go.
أرجوكم دعوني أذهب.
I will never--
لن أفعل ذلك أبداً--
Where's Yu? Did she take the day off?
أين يو؟ هل أخذت إجازة اليوم؟
I don't know. She didn't say a word.
لا أعرف. لم تنطق بكلمة واحدة.
She didn't text back in the group chat or answer her phone.
لم ترد على الرسائل النصية في دردشة المجموعة ولم تجب على هاتفها.
Damn it. What's up with her?
اللعنة! ما الذي يحدث معها؟
Miss, are you okay?
آنسة، هل أنتِ بخير؟
Pin-yu.
بين يو.
Are you okay? What happened?
هل أنت بخير؟ ماذا حدث؟
Are you a family member of Miss Chou?
هل أنت أحد أفراد عائلة الآنسة تشو؟
Yes, I am.
نعم أنا.
We received a report about her standing by the platform,
تلقينا تقريراً يفيد بوقوفها بجانب الرصيف،
looking disoriented.
يبدو عليه الارتباك.
We did notice she was a bit mentally unstable,
لاحظنا أنها كانت تعاني من بعض عدم الاستقرار النفسي،
so we called her family to pick her up just to be safe.
لذلك اتصلنا بعائلتها ليأتوا ويأخذوها من باب الاحتياط.
You hung up on me when we were on the phone yesterday.
أغلقت الخط في وجهي عندما كنا نتحدث عبر الهاتف أمس.
I called again, but you didn't answer, so I went to your place to look for you.
اتصلت بك مرة أخرى، لكنك لم تجب، لذلك ذهبت إلى منزلك لأبحث عنك.
The building manager said he saw you leave in a daze.
قال مدير المبنى إنه رآك تغادر وأنت في حالة ذهول.
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
If I said
لو قلت
I was possessed by a ghost, would you believe me?
لقد تلبسني شبح، هل تصدقني؟
Possessed by a ghost?
هل تلبسك روح؟
I don't even remember why I went to the platform.
لا أتذكر حتى سبب ذهابي إلى الرصيف.
I only remember
لا أتذكر سوى
being in the middle of our call.
كان ذلك في منتصف مكالمتنا.
Hey, sis.
مرحباً يا أختي.
Listen.
يستمع.
I think I saw that girl again tonight.
أعتقد أنني رأيت تلك الفتاة مرة أخرى الليلة.
Are you looking for me?
هل تبحث عني؟
Welcome to Rising Radio.
أهلاً بكم في راديو رايزينغ.
You're listening to New Life with Classical.
أنت تستمع الآن إلى برنامج "حياة جديدة مع موسيقى كلاسيكية".
Let classical music enter your life.
دع الموسيقى الكلاسيكية تدخل حياتك.
I may not be able to see the world clearly with my eyes.
قد لا أستطيع رؤية العالم بوضوح بعيني.
But that doesn't mean I can't hear the beauty of the world.
لكن هذا لا يعني أنني لا أستطيع سماع جمال العالم.
Welcome.
مرحباً.
Let me connect with you through music and my voice.
دعني أتواصل معك من خلال الموسيقى وصوتي.
Good evening, friends.
مساء الخير أيها الأصدقاء.
The first piece I'd like to introduce to you today is
أول قطعة أود أن أقدمها لكم اليوم هي
"Clair de lune" by Debussy.
"ضوء القمر" لديبوسي.
This is also one of my favorite classical pieces.
هذه أيضاً واحدة من مقطوعاتي الكلاسيكية المفضلة.
Later, I'll explain the origin of this piece
سأشرح لاحقاً أصل هذه القطعة
and why I like it.
ولماذا يعجبني ذلك.
We all know that
كلنا نعلم ذلك
there aren't many things in life that truly make us happy.
لا توجد أشياء كثيرة في الحياة تجعلنا سعداء حقاً.
We also tend to look on the bright side,
كما أننا نميل إلى النظر إلى الجانب المشرق،
to guard that rarely found happiness,
لحماية تلك السعادة النادرة،
to keep it in mind.
أن نضع ذلك في الاعتبار.
Recently, I encountered something which made me realize
مؤخراً، واجهت شيئاً جعلني أدرك
we feel unhappy most of the time, maybe because…
نشعر بالتعاسة في معظم الأوقات، ربما لأن...
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Which part of the footage would you like to start with?
من أي جزء من اللقطات ترغب في البدء؟
Sometime after half past ten yesterday.
في وقت ما بعد الساعة العاشرة والنصف من مساء أمس.
That's it.
هذا كل شيء.
Were you crying?
هل كنت تبكي؟
That wasn't me.
لم أكن أنا.
It was her.
كانت هي.
TAIWAN'S CRUELEST SERIAL KILLER OF ALL TIME
أكثر قاتل متسلسل وحشية في تاريخ تايوان
MOTHER OF OUYANG TI FIRST TO DISCOVER CRIME SCENE
والدة أويانغ تي أول من اكتشف مسرح الجريمة
LI JEN-YAO
لي جين ياو
DEATH PENALTY, RAINSTORM KILLER
لي جين ياو، عقوبة الإعدام، قاتل العاصفة المطرية
Why did she look up Li Jen-yao?
لماذا بحثت عن لي جين ياو؟
What's their relationship?
ما هي طبيعة علاقتهما؟
If she didn't possess my body to make me kill myself,
لو لم تكن تملك جسدي لتجعلني أقتل نفسي،
then what did she want?
إذن ماذا كانت تريد؟
She wanted to go somewhere.
أرادت الذهاب إلى مكان ما.
She wanted to find him.
أرادت أن تجده.
Pin-yu.
بين يو.
Why did she want to find him? She didn't show up in my research.
لماذا أرادت العثور عليه؟ لم تظهر في بحثي.
But Li Jen-yao killed so many people.
لكن لي جين ياو قتل الكثير من الناس.
Are there still victims who haven't been found?
هل لا يزال هناك ضحايا لم يتم العثور عليهم؟
-Pin-yu. -So…
-بين يو. -لذا…
She wanted to take revenge on him through me.
أرادت الانتقام منه من خلالي.
Chou Pin-yu.
تشو بين يو.
It's okay. Why don't you take a break first?
لا بأس. لماذا لا تأخذ استراحة أولاً؟
You're tired, aren't you?
أنت متعب، أليس كذلك؟
Have you thought that the overwhelming mental stress
هل فكرت في أن الضغط النفسي الهائل
from dealing with a cruel murderer at work,
من التعامل مع قاتل قاسٍ في العمل،
your recent move,
انتقالك الأخير،
and the scary rumors you heard
والشائعات المخيفة التي سمعتها
might be causing hallucinations?
هل يمكن أن يسبب الهلوسة؟
This is not good for you.
هذا ليس جيداً لك.
Move back in with me first.
انتقل للعيش معي أولاً.
I told you, they weren't hallucinations.
قلت لك، لم تكن مجرد هلوسات.
I've never sleepwalked.
لم أقم بالمشي أثناء النوم قط.
I know that wasn't me.
أعلم أن ذلك لم يكن أنا.
-Ta-wei. -Hey, Chou Pin-yu, you're still sleeping?
-تا-وي. -مهلاً، تشو بين-يو، هل ما زلت نائماً؟
Did you forget about the interview today?
هل نسيت أمر المقابلة اليوم؟
You ignored my calls and messages. What were you doing?
تجاهلت مكالماتي ورسائلي. ماذا كنت تفعل؟
Sorry. Something came up today.
معذرةً، لقد طرأ أمرٌ ما اليوم.
I'll get there right away.
سأصل إلى هناك فوراً.
All right. Be quick.
حسناً. أسرع.
I forgot I had work today.
نسيت أن لدي عمل اليوم.
I'm going to change.
سأتغير.
Sis.
أخت.
Thank you for coming to get me.
شكراً لك على مجيئك لأخذي.
I made you worry again.
لقد جعلتك تقلق مرة أخرى.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
It's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
Go get changed and head to work first.
اذهب لتغيير ملابسك وانطلق إلى العمل أولاً.
If you analyze these murders based on when Li Jen-yao committed them
إذا قمت بتحليل جرائم القتل هذه بناءً على وقت ارتكاب لي جين ياو لها
rather than when the bodies were found,
بدلاً من وقت العثور على الجثث،
you will notice
ستلاحظ
the first murder was more like an impulsive crime.
كانت جريمة القتل الأولى أشبه بجريمة اندفاعية.
The scene showed signs of a rushed cleanup.
أظهر المشهد علامات على عملية تنظيف متسرعة.
And the body appeared hastily handled.
وبدا أن الجثة قد تم التعامل معها على عجل.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
In the following murders,
في جرائم القتل التالية،
you can tell he became a different person.
يمكنك أن تلاحظ أنه أصبح شخصًا مختلفًا.
He began to act more carefully.
بدأ يتصرف بحذر أكبر.
He carried out the killings more and more skillfully.
نفّذ عمليات القتل بمهارة متزايدة.
The crime scenes were cleaned up more thoroughly.
تم تنظيف مواقع الجريمة بشكل أكثر دقة.
We could hardly find
بالكاد استطعنا أن نجد
any traces of him at the crime scenes.
أي آثار له في مسرح الجريمة.
As he continued killing,
وبينما كان يواصل القتل،
he became more cold-blooded.
أصبح أكثر قسوة.
As in the murder of Lin Meng-hung,
كما في جريمة قتل لين مينغ هونغ،
Li Jen-yao said himself
قال لي جين ياو بنفسه
that, after killing Lin Meng-hung, he ate the noodles Lin had cooked.
أنه بعد قتل لين مينغ هونغ، أكل المعكرونة التي طبخها لين.
You can imagine how ruthless he must be
يمكنك أن تتخيل مدى قسوته.
to be able to eat at the murder scene.
أن يكون قادراً على تناول الطعام في مسرح الجريمة.
Think of how indifferent one must be to killing to do that.
تخيل مدى اللامبالاة التي يجب أن يتحلى بها المرء تجاه القتل حتى يفعل ذلك.
Officer Lao.
الضابط لاو.
Based on what I read in the news
بناءً على ما قرأته في الأخبار
from the time Chang En-ya was killed,
منذ مقتل تشانغ إن يا،
Li Jen-yao burned something at the scene, but the news didn't say what.
أحرق لي جين ياو شيئاً ما في مكان الحادث، لكن الأخبار لم تذكر ماهيته.
I'm wondering if you could tell us
أتساءل عما إذا كان بإمكانك إخبارنا
if he burned incriminating evidence.
إذا قام بحرق الأدلة التي تدينه.
No.
لا.
What Li Jen-yao burned
ما أحرقه لي جين ياو
were some photos he took from Chang En-ya's place
كانت هذه بعض الصور التي التقطها من منزل تشانغ إن يا
and a piece of
وقطعة من
ballet wear.
ملابس الباليه.
I wonder, Officer,
أتساءل يا حضرة الضابط،
in your personal opinion,
برأيك الشخصي،
what's so special about Li Jen-yao as a murderer?
ما الذي يميز لي جين ياو كقاتل؟
There is something.
هناك شيء ما.
All criminals, even those who turn themselves in,
جميع المجرمين، حتى أولئك الذين يسلمون أنفسهم،
try their best to gloss over the key parts in their confessions.
يبذلون قصارى جهدهم للتغاضي عن الأجزاء الرئيسية في اعترافاتهم.
But Li Jen-yao
لكن لي جين ياو
is the most cooperative criminal I've ever seen.
إنه أكثر مجرم متعاون رأيته في حياتي.
From the methods used to the timeline and locations,
بدءًا من الأساليب المستخدمة وصولًا إلى الجدول الزمني والمواقع،
to how the bodies were disposed of, he was honest about everything.
كان صادقاً بشأن كل شيء ، حتى فيما يتعلق بكيفية التخلص من الجثث .
But I just don't understand why he wouldn't share one thing.
لكنني لا أفهم لماذا لم يشاركني شيئاً واحداً.
What is that?
ما هذا؟
His motive.
دافعه.
Legally, it no longer matters whether he killed nine or ten people.
من الناحية القانونية، لم يعد يهم ما إذا كان قد قتل تسعة أشخاص أو عشرة.
But he simply won't say why he had to kill these people
لكنه ببساطة يرفض أن يقول لماذا اضطر إلى قتل هؤلاء الناس
and how he targeted them.
وكيف استهدفهم.
That's why I feel like
لهذا السبب أشعر بـ
he did what he did to hide some kind of secret.
لقد فعل ما فعل لإخفاء نوع من السر.
Just like people tell many lies
تمامًا كما يكذب الناس كثيرًا
to cover up a single thing.
للتغطية على شيء واحد.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll organize the materials from the interview with Officer Lao
سأقوم بتنظيم المواد من المقابلة مع الضابط لاو
and send them to you. Okay.
وسأرسلها إليك. حسناً.
Ma'am.
سيدتي.
No.
لا.
You're in a uniform, so you should be younger than me.
أنت ترتدي زيًا رسميًا، لذا يجب أن تكون أصغر مني سنًا.
But that might not be true.
لكن هذا قد لا يكون صحيحاً.
Whatever.
أيا كان.
Miss.
يفتقد.
I just want you to know,
أردت فقط أن تعلم،
although we're from different worlds, I've always respected you.
رغم اختلاف عوالمنا، فقد كنت دائماً أحترمك.
I know you arrived first, and I may have disturbed you,
أعلم أنك وصلت أولاً، وربما أكون قد أزعجتك.
but I've paid rent and the deposit for two months.
لكنني دفعت الإيجار والتأمين لشهرين.
You can't ask me to move out.
لا يمكنك أن تطلب مني أن أغادر.
I'll move out once I find a place.
سأنتقل من هنا حالما أجد مكاناً.
But before then,
لكن قبل ذلك،
please give me a chance to negotiate.
أرجو أن تمنحني فرصة للتفاوض.
I know we're from different worlds.
أعلم أننا من عوالم مختلفة.
You shouldn't take it out on me even if you were wronged.
لا ينبغي أن تُفرغ غضبك عليّ حتى لو كنت قد تعرضت للظلم.
It's not very nice of you to possess me whenever you want.
ليس من اللائق أن تمتلكني وقتما تشاء.
You should go to the person who hurt you.
يجب عليك الذهاب إلى الشخص الذي آذاك.
Also,
أيضًا،
please don't appear out of the blue.
أرجوك لا تظهر فجأة.
Otherwise, I'll get scared.
وإلا سأشعر بالخوف.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
After moving in,
بعد الانتقال إلى المنزل،
have you heard heels clacking at night
هل سمعت صوت ارتطام الكعب العالي في الليل؟
or your doorbell ringing continuously?
أم أن جرس بابك يرن باستمرار؟
Hey.
يا.
I was afraid you'd imagine things being home alone.
كنت أخشى أن تتخيل أن الأمور ستكون على ما يرام في المنزل.
Late-night snacks.
وجبات خفيفة في وقت متأخر من الليل.
You're the best.
أنت الأفضل.
I have something to do. Gotta go.
لديّ بعض الأمور لأفعلها. يجب أن أذهب.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
You slept soundly last night.
لقد نمت نوماً عميقاً الليلة الماضية.
Nothing happened.
لم يحدث شيء.
Is it really fine now?
هل الوضع جيد حقاً الآن؟
-Here's your package. -Thank you.
- تفضل طردك. - شكراً لك.
-It must be tough. -No worries.
- لا بد أن الأمر صعب. - لا تقلق.
Ma'am, excuse me. I want to ask you something.
سيدتي، معذرةً. أريد أن أسألك شيئاً.
Last time, you told me about the girl who used to rent the place I'm living in.
في المرة الماضية، أخبرتني عن الفتاة التي كانت تستأجر المكان الذي أعيش فيه.
How did she die?
كيف ماتت؟
What was her name?
ما اسمها؟
Sis, listen.
يا أختي، اسمعي.
The previous tenant's name was Chang En-ya.
كان اسم المستأجر السابق تشانغ إن-يا.
She was one of Li Jen-yao's victims.
كانت إحدى ضحايا لي جين ياو.
Just hearing that gives me goosebumps.
مجرد سماع ذلك يصيبني بالقشعريرة.
But
لكن
Chang En-ya wasn't the high school girl I saw.
لم تكن تشانغ إن يا هي فتاة المدرسة الثانوية التي رأيتها.
I'm busy now.
أنا مشغول الآن.
I'll talk to you later, okay?
سأتحدث إليك لاحقاً، حسناً؟
Okay. I'll leave you to it.
حسناً، سأتركك وشأنك.
Li Jen-yao.
لي جين ياو.
Subtitle translation by: Hannah Liu
ترجمة الترجمة المصاحبة: هانا ليو